export const CHRISTIANRELIGIOUSSTUDIESA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. God blessed and hallowed the seventh day because it was a day of ______________",
A: "Fast",
B: "Worship",
C: "Praise",
D: "Rest",
answer: "D. Rest",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Adam was placed in the garden of Eden located in the __________",
A: "East",
B: "West",
C: "North",
D: "South",
answer: "A. East",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The creation of woman was necessitated by the need for ____________",
A: "Consultation",
B: "Companionship",
C: "Love",
D: "Solidarity",
answer: "B. Companionship",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Jacob showed preference for Joseph because, Joseph________________",
A: "Always spoke the truth",
B: "Had the spirit of God in him",
C: "Loved his brother unconditionally",
D: "Was born in his old age",
answer: "D. Was born in his old age",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The main reason for which Joseph's brothers sold him was __________________",
A: "Love for money",
B: "Jealousy",
C: "Desire to eliminate others",
D: "Hatred",
answer: "D. Hatred",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Shiphrah and Puah refused to obey Pharaoh because______________",
A: "Pharaoh wanted to kill the Israelite babies",
B: "Pharaoh wanted to control the Hebrew population",
C: "They were kinsmen of the Israelites",
D: "They were women who feared God",
answer: "D. They were women who feared God",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. But behold, they will not believe me or listen to my voice, for they will say, the Lord did not appear to you. Who made this remark?",
A: "Aaron",
B: "Moses",
C: "Joseph",
D: "Jacob",
answer: "B. Moses",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The Israelites asked Aaron to make gods for them because they___________",
A: "Wanted a god to lead them back to Egypt",
B: "Felt God had neglected them due to their sins",
C: "Felt Moses had delayed on Mount Sinai",
D: "Were under severe attack by the Egyptians",
answer: "C. Felt Moses had delayed on Mount Sinai",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Joshua was invested with some of Moses authority so that the Israelites might______________",
A: "Honour him",
B: "Bless him",
C: "Purify him",
D: "Obey him",
answer: "D. Obey him",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Barak deployed a troop of then thousand men as advised by Deborah on Mount____________",
A: "Tabor",
B: "Sina",
C: "Gillboa",
D: "Nebo",
answer: "A. Tabor",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. It is the Lord, let Him do what seems good to Him. These words were said ___________",
A: "Saul",
B: "Samuel",
C: "Moses",
D: "Eli",
answer: "D. Eli",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The glory has departed from Israel was the meaning of the name ____________",
A: "Samuel",
B: "Eli",
C: "Phinehas",
D: "Ichabod",
answer: "D. Ichabod",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Prophet Samuel, like Eli, had two worthless sons called ___________",
A: "Joel and Abihu",
B: "Nadab and Abihu",
C: "Joel and Abijah",
D: "Gershom and Abijah.",
answer: "C. Joel and Abijah",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. David entered into Saul's service because he was _________",
A: "A skillful musician",
B: "Prudent in speech",
C: "An intelligent warrior",
D: "A man after God's heart",
answer: "A. A skillful musician",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. I have done wrong; return, my son David, for I will no more do you harm because my life was precious in your eyes this day;...... who made this statement?",
A: "Samuel",
B: "Joab",
C: "Abner",
D: "Saul",
answer: "D. Saul",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The first child David had with Bathsheba died on the _________",
A: "third day",
B: "seventh day",
C: "eleventh day",
D: "fifteenth day",
answer: "B. seventh day",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Solomon asked God for an understanding mind to govern Israel so that he could_________",
A: "rule in peace",
B: "develop the nation",
C: "discern what is right",
D: "build the temple",
answer: "C. discern what is right",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. During the dedication of the temple by Solomon, the cloud which filled the house symbolized the _________",
A: "angels",
B: "saints",
C: "glory of God",
D: "righteousness of the people.",
answer: "C. glory of God",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. To your tents, O Israel! Look now to your own house. David. This call was made because____________",
A: "Rehoboam increased the Northern Kingdom's burden",
B: "Solomon favoured the Southern kingdom",
C: "Solomon imposed heavy taxes on the people",
D: "Rehoboam refused to grant the Northerners' petition.",
answer: "C. Solomon imposed heavy taxes on the people",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. During the reign of King Ahab, Hiel of Bethel rebuilt Jericho at the cost of the lives of his children____________",
A: "Amram and Adonijah",
B: "Hophni and Phinehas",
C: "Abinadab and Malchishua",
D: "Abiram and Segub",
answer: "D. Abiram and Segub",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. As a result of King Ahab's sin, the people of Israel suffered_____________",
A: "pestilence",
B: "drought",
C: "plague",
D: "earthquake.",
answer: "B. drought",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Naboth was killed so that____________",
A: "God might punish Ahab and Jezebel",
B: "Ahab's authority would prevail",
C: "Ahab might own his property",
D: "Ahab might stop fasting",
answer: "C. Ahab might own his property",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The aftermath of Gehazi's actions led to Elisha__________",
A: "rebuking him for his greed",
B: "commending him for his cleverness",
C: "pronouncing a curse on him and his generation",
D: "stopping Gehazi from working with him",
answer: "C. pronouncing a curse on him and his generation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. King Josiah was inspired to reform the worship of God in Judah by the____________",
A: "Priests of Yahweh",
B: "Temple secretary, Shaphan",
C: "Workers repairing the temple",
D: "contents of the book of the law",
answer: "D. contents of the book of the law",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The death of Josiah occurred when he_______",
A: "crossed the Jordan to Hazor",
B: "fought Pharaoh Neco at Megiddo",
C: "fought the Babylonians at UR",
D: "took his reforms to the North",
answer: "A. crossed the Jordan to Hazor",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which factor influenced King Artaxerxes to favour Nehemiah?",
A: "Faithfulness",
B: "Tolerance",
C: "Obedience",
D: "Prayer",
answer: "C. Obedience",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Before rebuilding the wall of Jerusalem, Nehemiah first ____________",
A: "confided in a few people with his plan",
B: "called a general meeting to assess the damage",
C: "studied and assessed the extent of the damage",
D: "attacked the arch enemies of Judah",
answer: "C. studied and assessed the extent of the damage",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The excellent spirit in Daniel caused the Satraps to be_____________________________",
A: "Angry with him",
B: "Jealous of him",
C: "Bitter with him",
D: "Friendly with him.",
answer: "B. Jealous of him",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. In the book of Amos, selling the needy for a pair of shoes means_____________",
A: "the needy had the same value as shoes",
B: "the needy did not need shoes",
C: "shoes were much more valuable than the needy",
D: "the rich dishonored the less privileged.",
answer: "D. the rich dishonoured the less privileged.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. According to Amos, the day of the Lord for the Jews would be a day of_________",
A: "Light",
B: "Famine",
C: "Darkness",
D: "Success",
answer: "D. Success",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The temptations of Jesus were meant to_______________________",
A: "make Him the Son of God",
B: "prepare Him for His ministry",
C: "help Him to overcome the devil",
D: "make Him a wonder-working Messiah.",
answer: "B. prepare Him for His ministry",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Follow me, and I will make you fishers of men. This was addressed to_______________",
A: "James and John",
B: "Peter and John",
C: "James and Andrew",
D: "Simon and Andrew",
answer: "D. Simon and Andrew",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of these people were sons of Zebedee?",
A: "Peter and John",
B: "James and Simon",
C: "Andrew and Peter",
D: "John and James.",
answer: "D. John and James.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. According to the Gospel of Matthew, the first two disciples of Jesus were_______________",
A: "Tax collectors",
B: "Farmers",
C: "Fishermen",
D: "Tentmakers.",
answer: "C. Fishermen",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. And as he passed on, he saw Levi the son of Alphaeus sitting at the tax office,.. What did Jesus say to Levi?",
A: "Take your pallet and walk",
B: "Follow me",
C: "Rise up",
D: "I will make you a fisher of men",
answer: "B. Follow me",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Sit here, while I go yonder and pray. Jesus gave this instruction to the disciples at__________",
A: "Bethany",
B: "Capernaum",
C: "Golgotha",
D: "Gethsemane",
answer: "D. Gethsemane",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. My father, if it be possible, let this cup pass from me,....'Cup' as used here refers to______",
A: "Judgement",
B: "Death",
C: "Trial",
D: "Temptation",
answer: "B. Death",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. After the arrest of Jesus in the garden of Gethsemane, He was first taken to the courtyard of ________",
A: "Pilate",
B: "Caiaphas",
C: "Herod the Great",
D: "Herod Antipas.",
answer: "B. Caiaphas",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Why do we still need witnesses? You have now heard his blasphemy This remark was made by________",
A: "Pontius Pilate",
B: "The Roman Governor",
C: "The High Priest",
D: "The Sanhedrin",
answer: "D. The Sanhedrin",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. How was the sepulcher in which Jesus was laid secured by the Chief Priests?",
A: "Fixing a stone door and a lock",
B: "Rolling a hewn rock to the entrance",
C: "Setting a guard of Roman Soldiers",
D: "Sealing the stone and setting a guard",
answer: "B. Rolling a hewn rock to the entrance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The reason for the election of Matthias to replace Judas was to_______________",
A: "Show Peter's authority as a leader",
B: "Fulfil the words of the scripture",
C: "End the curse of Judas",
D: "Add more people for the work",
answer: "B. Fulfil the words of the scripture",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The apostles preferred preaching to serving tables because__________",
A: "they were not called for alms giving",
B: "the Hellenists were complaining too much about discrimination",
C: "they were to devote themselves to prayer and the word",
D: "Serving tables was a tedious task for them",
answer: "C. they were to devote themselves to prayer and the word",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. For thou will not abandon my soul to Hades, nor let thy Holy one see corruption. Peter Used this Psalm of David to defend Jesus'",
A: "temptation",
B: "crucifixion",
C: "resurrection",
D: "baptism",
answer: "C. resurrection",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Saul was a native of___________________",
A: "Joppa",
B: "Tarsus",
C: "Damascus",
D: "Jerusalem",
answer: "B. Tarsus",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. King Herod arrested Peter because__________",
A: "he hated the apostles",
B: "he was the leader of the apostles",
C: "he was very notorious",
D: "James death pleased the jews",
answer: "D. James death pleased the jews",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. To make prayers effective, James taught that Christians should____________",
A: "pray without ceasing",
B: "pray in tongues",
C: "have congregational prayers",
D: "avoid double mindedness",
answer: "D. avoid double mindedness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The Church demonstrates partiality when she___________",
A: "accords the poor much respect",
B: "respects the rich during worship",
C: "reserves the best seats for rich",
D: "treats her members with impunity",
answer: "C. reserves the best seats for rich",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Peter said that, when church elders tend their flock well, they would obtain__________",
A: "the crown of glory",
B: "prosperity",
C: "love and holiness",
D: "peace",
answer: "A. the crown of glory",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. According to Peter, a good citizen is one who____________",
A: "builds houses and rents to those who do not have",
B: "provides transports at reduced cost of other citizens",
C: "obeys the laws of the state and fulfils his obligations",
D: "helps to finance the government at all times.",
answer: "C. obeys the laws of the state and fulfils his obligations",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Live as freemen, yet without using your freedom as a pretext for evil. Peter, by this text was calling on Christians to ___________",
A: "resist the devil always",
B: "do what is right",
C: "fight for their freedom",
D: "endure pain while",
answer: "B. do what is right",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]